[Music]
[音乐]
coming
未来
my name is two remarks to work in the
我的名字是两句话要在
core libraries team in the Java platform
Java平台中的核心库团队
group at Oracle I work on Java and the
Oracle的一个小组，我从事Java和
JDK and one of the things I work on is
JDK和我从事的工作之一是
the collections framework so the talk
收集框架，所以谈论
today is collections refueled and so
今天收集了很多东西，所以
collections has long history I'm going
我要去的收藏历史悠久
to do a very very brief history that I
做一个非常非常简短的历史，我
am going to spend some time talking
要花一些时间说话
about Java 8
关于Java 8
even though Java 8 has been out for
即使Java 8已经推出
almost 3 years now there are some
现在快三年了
interesting features that were added to
添加到的有趣功能
collections Java 8 that don't seem to
似乎没有的Java 8集合
get enough publicity so I'm going to
得到足够的宣传，所以我要
talk about those a little bit and then
谈一些，然后
move on to some new features in Java 9
继续介绍Java 9中的一些新功能
so there's a Twitter hashtag collections
所以有一个Twitter标签集合
revealed you can see that up at the
透露你可以在那看到
upper right so if you want to tweet to
右上角，所以如果你想发推
me during or after the presentation I
在演讲过程中或演讲后我
will look at that hashtag and respond to
将查看该标签并响应
any questions there or it's a small it's
那里有任何问题，或者很小
a small crowd if I have time we can take
一小群人，如果我有时间我们可以带走
questions at the end and I'll be around
最后的问题，我会在附近
the conference for the rest of the
剩下的会议
afternoon as well alright so history of
下午还好，所以历史
collections so Java is now over 20 years
Java集合已经有20多年了
old and the collections framework is not
旧的收藏夹框架不是
quite as old as Java it is is almost
与Java差不多古老
almost twenty years old the java 1.0 was
Java 1.0已有近二十年的历史了
introduced with what we now call the
介绍了我们现在所说的
legacy collection so there was no
旧版收藏，所以没有
collections framework in the very
收集框架
beginning the old things vector and hash
开始旧事物矢量和哈希
table or hash table as some of us call
表或哈希表，就像我们中的一些人所说的那样
it but those were replaced in jdk 1.2
它，但那些已在jdk 1.2中替换
and that's the collection framework that
这就是收集框架
we're all familiar with with the
我们都熟悉
interfaces collection list set map and
接口集合列表集映射和
so forth and the concrete classes to
等等，以及具体的课程
back them up the usual usual suspects
支持他们通常的犯罪嫌疑人
ArrayList hash map hash set and so forth
ArrayList哈希图哈希集等等
so those were introduced in 1998 and so
所以这些是在1998年推出的
that was nineteen years ago and so those
那是19年前，所以那些
are in in use daily in fact the paper
实际上每天都在使用
just came out
刚出来
a few weeks ago or actuals pre-published
几周前或实际发布
it's going to be published at the
它将会在
conference this this summer I think
我认为今年夏天的发布会
basically did an empirical study of the
基本上对
usage of collections and it turns out
集合的使用结果
ArrayList surprise surprise is the most
ArrayList惊喜最大
used collection in Java some some very
Java中使用过的集合
large fraction might have even been a
很大一部分甚至可能是
majority of uses of collections our
收藏品的大部分用途
ArrayList so moving on quickly in Java 5
ArrayList，以便在Java 5中快速进行
in 2004 generics were added to the
2004年，将仿制药添加到
language and that had a huge impact on
语言，这对
the collections api's and so by now I
集合api的，所以现在我
hope everybody is converted over to
希望大家都转化为
using genericized collections instead of
使用通用集合而不是
instead of the original raw collections
而不是原始的原始收藏
and the other big addition in Java 5 was
Java 5中的另一个重要补充是
the addition of the concurrent
并发的加法
collections I'm not going to be talking
我不会谈论的收藏
about those today but that's a whole
关于今天的那些，但这是一个整体
whole kind of related framework that has
完整的相关框架
some overlap with the collections
与集合有些重叠
framework and then along the way various
框架，然后沿途各种各样
individual implementations were added in
个别实现已添加
various releases such as a ray deck
各种版本，如射线甲板
priority to you know new mapping room
您知道新映射室的优先级
set and so forth so those are very
设置等等，所以那些非常
specialized collections they don't get
他们没有得到的专业收藏
much general use but when you need them
一般用途，但在需要时使用
they're there and they are really useful
他们在那里，他们真的很有用
alright so Java 8 collections
好的，所以Java 8集合
enhancements so I think most people are
增强功能，所以我认为大多数人
aware that the big features of Java 8
意识到Java 8的主要功能
were lambdas were added to the
将lambda添加到
programming language and the streams API
编程语言和流API
was was added to the core libraries so
被添加到核心库中
you know really interesting feature
你知道真正有趣的功能
really useful I hope everybody is using
真的有用，我希望每个人都在使用
them but backing them up are some
他们，但支持他们一些
additional language features in
中的其他语言功能
particular interfaces can now have
特定接口现在可以具有
default methods and static methods so
默认方法和静态方法
that's that's an interesting language
那是一种有趣的语言
feature I'm not going to talk about the
功能我不会谈论
language enhancements themselves what I
语言增强本身就是我
do want to talk about is the way we use
想说的是我们使用的方式
those language features in the JDK to
JDK中的那些语言功能
enhance the collection framework in JDK
增强JDK中的收集框架
8 and so what we did was for the first
8，所以我们要做的是第一次
time I say the first time ever in 15
我说15年来第一次
years I think for the first time ever we
几年来，我想我们第一次
actually added
实际添加
methods to the collections interfaces
集合接口的方法
and so that was a big deal about default
因此，这与违约大不相同
methods prior to default methods you
默认方法之前的方法
could not compatibly add methods to an
无法兼容地将方法添加到
interface otherwise would Budhia it
界面否则会Budhia吗
would be an incompatibility
将是不兼容的
so in java 8 with the addition of
所以在Java 8中
default methods it's now possible to add
默认方法，现在可以添加
methods to interfaces and we went ahead
接口的方法，我们继续
it did so and so collection let's get er
它做到了，所以收集让我们得到
able ya iterable collection list got a
能雅可迭代的收藏列表有一个
few new methods map map and comparator
几个新方法map映射和比较器
and spend a little more time on because
多花点时间在
they got quite a number of new methods
他们有了很多新方法
the interesting thing about this well
关于这口井的有趣之处
couple interest a bunch of interesting
一对夫妇有趣的一堆
things those new methods were i mean it
那些新方法是我的意思
it's not a requirement that new methods
并不需要新方法
have to use lambda but a lot of those
必须使用lambda，但其中很多
new methods were added from the
从中添加了新方法
standpoint of oh now that we have this
哦，现在我们有了这个
new method when we when that new method
当我们使用新方法时
can accept a lambda it can do many more
可以接受lambda，它可以做更多的事情
powerful things so i have a bunch of
强大的东西，所以我有一堆
examples of that starting effect on the
对
next slide so the iterable interface has
下一张幻灯片，因此可迭代的界面具有
been there since java 5 but basically it
自Java 5以来就在那里
allows you to use the enhanced for-loop
允许您使用增强的for循环
so in java 7 here I've kind of pairs of
所以在Java 7中，我对
code snippets on the top there's Java 7
顶部的代码段是Java 7
and then down below a rewrite of that in
然后在下面重写
Java 8 and so in Java 7 if you wanted to
Java 8以及Java 7，如果您想
iterate over lists you could use the the
遍历列表，您可以使用
officially it's called the enhanced
正式称为增强型
for-loop some people call it the for
for-loop有些人称其为
each loop I tend to avoid calling in
每个循环我倾向于避免调用
that because there's now a method called
那是因为现在有一个叫做
for each so Java 7 you write the
对于每个Java 7，您都可以编写
enhanced for-loop
增强for循环
but in Java 8 what you can do is call
但是在Java 8中，您可以做的是调用
the for each method and pass it a lambda
对于每种方法，并将其传递给lambda
and what it does is it executes that
它执行的是执行
lambda on each element in that list and
该列表中每个元素的lambda和
so that's that's a little syntactic
这就是一点句法
nicety but interval is inherited by
不错，但间隔是由继承的
every collection implementation so all
每个集合的实现
the collections are now enhanced by
现在通过以下方式增强了收藏
having this for each method on them and
每个方法都有这个
in fact indeed all the other methods all
实际上所有其他方法
the other default methods are inherited
其他默认方法是继承的
all the way down the hierarchy so what
一直到层次结构
we've done is by adding default methods
我们所做的是通过添加默认方法
we have enhanced every existing
我们已经增强了每个现有的
collection even ones that were were not
收集甚至不是
introduced
引进
in Java 8 alright continuing on the
在Java 8中继续
iterable actually this is iterator not
可迭代，实际上这不是迭代器
iterable but if you've ever written an
迭代，但如果您曾经写过
iterator you had to write has next
您必须编写的迭代器具有下一个
method and a next method and oh that's
方法和下一个方法，哦，那是
right you have to also write the remove
对，你还必须写删除
method well I don't want to support
方法很好，我不想支持
removal so you always wrote throw new
删除，所以你总是写抛出新的
unsupported operation exception and so
不支持的操作异常等
now there's a default method on iterator
现在在迭代器上有一个默认方法
called
叫
remove there's a default implementation
删除有一个默认实现
which simply throws unsupported
只是抛出不受支持的
operation exceptions so this is really
操作异常，所以这真的
nothing more than convenience if you're
无非就是方便
writing your own iterator you simply if
编写自己的迭代器
you if you don't override remove you you
如果您不覆盖您，则将您删除
well you don't have to override remove
好吧，您不必覆盖删除
anymore and if you don't you get the
不再，如果你不明白
default behavior which is to throw an
默认行为是抛出一个
exception which is pretty often what you
你经常遇到的例外
want because they're relatively few
想要，因为他们相对较少
iterators support removal but if you do
迭代器支持删除，但如果您这样做
want to support removal in your iterator
想支持迭代器中的删除
you just go ahead and override it like
你只要继续并覆盖它像
you always did
你总是那样
alright now he thinks getting a little
好吧，他现在觉得有点
more interesting here because instead of
这里更有趣，因为
just sort of syntactic niceties we're
只是一种语法上的细微差别
getting into some bulk operations so
进行一些批量操作
suppose you have a case where you want
假设你有一个想要的情况
to run through a list and remove
遍历列表并删除
elements that match some criterion so in
符合某些条件的元素
Java 7 you could you had to write the
Java 7，您可能必须编写
for loop you had to write it out kind of
对于循环，您必须将其写出来
the old way by using an iterator so you
使用迭代器的旧方法
a key point here is that you cannot use
这里的关键是您不能使用
the enhanced for loop because you can't
增强的for循环，因为您不能
remove things from within a loop
从循环中删除事物
otherwise you will get a concurrent
否则你会得到一个并发
modification exception and so what you
修改异常等等你
had to do was fall back to the original
要做的是回到原始状态
loop loop using an iterator and then if
循环使用迭代器，然后如果
something matched you called remove on
与您匹配的东西称为“删除”
the iterator so that's the java 7 code
迭代器，所以是Java 7代码
and it it's it's kind of bulky
有点笨重
especially you know even compared to the
特别是与
to the enhanced Fork of the enhanced
到增强的Fork
for-loop code that that you would write
您将编写的for循环代码
if you weren't removing something now in
如果您现在不删除任何东西
java 8 there's a new method remove if
Java 8中有一个新方法删除
that takes a predicate and the semantics
需要一个predicate和语义
are that predicate is applied to each
predicate是否应用于每个predicate
element of that collection and if the
该集合的元素，如果
predicate returns true
predicate返回true
then it removes it from the collection
然后将其从集合中删除
and so that's that's pretty nice I mean
这就是我的意思。
so you look that that you know four or
所以你看起来知道四或
five line four loop there collapse down
五线四环那里倒塌了
to a single line makes things much nicer
一行可以使事情变得更好
but it's not only a syntactic advantage
不仅是语法上的优势
it's actually a performance advantage
这实际上是性能优势
and so if you consider iterating over an
因此，如果您考虑迭代一个
ArrayList if you remove something from
ArrayList，如果您从中删除某些内容
an ArrayList it has to have to shift all
一个ArrayList它必须将所有
the elements up in place and so if you
元素就位，所以如果您
do that repeatedly within an ArrayList
在ArrayList中重复做一次
then you get an order n-squared
那么你得到一个n平方的订单
performance because it's repeatedly
性能，因为它反复出现
shifting the tail of the ArrayList back
向后移ArrayList的尾部
up as as elements are deleted and so
就像删除元素一样
remove if in Java eight is optimized for
如果在Java中针对八项进行了优化，则删除
ArrayList what it does is it is it keeps
ArrayList的作用是保持
track of which things are removed and
跟踪哪些内容被删除以及
then does the copy and operation all at
然后在所有位置进行复制和操作
once and so we've reduced the algorithm
一次，所以我们减少了算法
from N squared to order n at the same
从N平方到n阶
time we've made the code a lot more
时候我们编写了更多代码
concise and so the the benefit here is
简洁，所以这里的好处是
that the remove if operation it's its
该删除如果操作是它的
internal iteration and it's raised the
内部迭代，它提出了
semantic level of the API so instead of
API的语义级别，因此代替
looking at the collection from the
从
outside and picking at things one at a
在外面，一挑一拣
time we're now saying okay remove all
现在我们说好的时间删除所有
the elements remove all the matching
元素删除所有匹配项
elements that's basically what this says
基本上就是这样的元素
so the implementation takes advantage of
因此实施利用了
that with a better algorithm all right
有了更好的算法
moving on more more new default methods
继续使用更多新的默认方法
the list interface has couple new
列表界面有几个新功能
methods on it one of them is replace all
方法之一，就是全部替换
and so what that does is it it replaces
所以它能代替它
every element in list with something
列表中的每个元素都有
else so suppose you wanted to do that in
否则，假设您想在
in Java 7 again you could use the the
在Java 7中，您可以再次使用
old fashioned or the original style of
老式的或原始的
for loop using a list iterator and then
使用列表迭代器进行循环，然后
the the example here is suppose you
这个例子是假设你
wanted to run through a list of strings
想遍历字符串列表
and convert them all to uppercase so you
并将它们全部转换为大写
could run a list iterator over the list
可以在列表上运行列表迭代器
and set each element to the element
并将每个元素设置为
converted uppercase so that's the top
转换后的大写字母，所以这是顶部
code snippet there but most people don't
那里的代码段，但大多数人没有
do that I don't does anybody ever
做到那我从来没有做过任何人
you list iterators any show of hands
您列出迭代器的任何举手
here no I think Lissa diretor I mean
在这里不，我想我的意思是Lissa diretor
it's it's interesting and powerful but I
这是有趣而强大的，但我
think nobody uses it and well and the
认为没有人很好地使用它，
reason is a if if you had different
原因是如果您有不同
kinds of lists then you would want to
种类的清单，那么您想要
use an abstract way to iterate over them
使用抽象的方式遍历它们
using lists iterators but since
使用列表迭代器，但由于
everybody is using an ArrayList you
每个人都在使用ArrayList
might as well just index into it and so
最好只是索引进去等等
that's the second code block here and I
那是这里的第二个代码块
think everybody would probably write it
认为每个人都可能会写
this way or you just index from zero to
这样或者你只是从零索引到
size and then set you know just call set
大小，然后设置您知道只是设置
and get using using the index operation
并使用索引操作
and that's perfectly fine if you know
如果你知道那很好
you're operating on an ArrayList if
您正在对ArrayList进行操作，如果
you're operating a linked list then that
您正在操作一个链表，然后
will slow drastically but you should be
会大大减慢速度，但是你应该
using linked lists anyway and that's
无论如何使用链接列表，那就是
that's a different talk so anyway in
那是另一回事，所以无论如何
Java eight this gets even better so we
Java 8变得更好，所以我们
just called the replace all method and
只是称为全部替换方法而
give it a lambda function or method
给它一个lambda函数或方法
reference in this case that transforms
这种情况下的参考
the element so we say string colon colon
这个元素，所以我们说字符串冒号冒号
to uppercase so it takes a string
大写，所以需要一个字符串
converts it to uppercase and replace all
将其转换为大写并替换所有
just runs through for every element
贯穿于每个元素
replaces it with its with its uppercase
用大写字母替换它
equivalent and so in one line we've
等价的，所以在一行中
replaced those loops that kind of did
取代了那种做的循环
things sort of one at a time now when
一次只发生一件事情
people see this they often say oh I want
人们看到这个，他们经常说哦，我想要
to change I want to change this list so
更改我想更改此列表，以便
that every element is is transformed
每个元素都被转化了
into something different of a different
变成不同的东西
type and you cannot do that with replace
键入，而替换则无法做到
all for that you need to use a stream
您需要使用流的全部
stream out the elements transform them
流出元素来转换它们
into something of different type and
变成不同类型的东西
then collect them into a new list
然后将它们收集到新列表中
alright so another method that was added
好了，所以添加了另一种方法
to the list interface is sort so well
到列表界面的排序很好
big deal instead of calling collections
大笔交易而不是催款
lot sort on a list just called list dot
在仅称为列表点的列表上进行排序
sort what does that buy you well a
排序是什么让你买得好
couple things so the the collections dot
几件事情，所以收集点
sort method had to operate on a list of
排序方法必须对列表进行操作
any implementation of
任何实施
and so the the most generic way to do
所以最通用的方式
that is to copy out the list elements
即复制出列表元素
into an array sort that in it would be a
到一个数组中排序将是一个
temporary array that was temporarily
临时数组
allocated just for the purpose of
仅出于以下目的分配
sorting sort the array in place and then
对数组进行排序，然后
copy all those elements back and so the
复制所有这些元素，所以
default implementation of list dot sort
列表点排序的默认实现
does exactly that because it doesn't
这样做是因为它没有
know who it's inherited by however
知道它是谁继承的
ArrayList dot sort again ArrayList being
ArrayList点再次排序ArrayList正在
the most commonly used collection
最常用的收藏
ArrayList dot sort overrides the default
ArrayList点排序将覆盖默认值
implementation and says hey I am an
实施，并说我是
ArrayList I know I have all my elements
ArrayList我知道我拥有所有元素
stored in internal in an internal array
存储在内部数组中
I'll just sort them in place in fact
我只是将它们排序到位
there's something called arrays dot sort
有一种叫做数组点排序的东西
so all it does is turn around and call a
所以它要做的就是转身并呼叫
raised dot sort on on its internal array
凸起的点在其内部数组上排序
and so we've we've saved a bunch of
所以我们已经保存了一堆
memory allocation and we saved a copy
内存分配，我们保存了副本
out and a copy back in so the override
出并复制回来，以便覆盖
of raela store actually is buying us
商店的人实际上正在购买我们
quite a bit here and in turn collections
这里有很多，反过来又是收藏
that sort simply turns around and called
那种转身就叫
sort on on the list that it's provided
在提供的列表上排序
so you don't even have to change your
所以你甚至不需要改变你的
code so if your code is using array
代码，如果您的代码使用数组
lists and you call collection dot sort
列表，然后调用集合点排序
you get this new behavior for free all
您将免费获得所有这种新行为
right now I'm moving on to map there are
现在我要去地图上
a whole bunch of methods added to map
一大堆方法添加到地图
but I'm going to run through I think the
但是我要经历
most some of the more interesting ones
大多数更有趣的
here but they're a lot more than I can
在这里，但是他们远远超出了我的能力
cover in this talk so in Java 7 if you
在本次演讲中介绍，因此在Java 7中
wanted to do something for every element
想为每个元素做点什么
of the map like print out you know print
像打印出来的地图一样，您知道打印
out the key the key value you know print
找出您要打印的键值
out each key in value you'd use you
列出您会使用的每个键值
usually do a loop over the entry set of
通常会在
the map and then do something useful
地图，然后做一些有用的事情
within that for loop and so in java 8
在for循环中，所以在java 8中
there's a for each on a map it's just
在地图上每个都有一个
kind of like the for each on interval
有点像每个间隔
except that instead of taking instead of
除了不取而代之
taking a function that takes one
采取一项需要一项的职能
argument
论点
by function which takes two arguments
通过带有两个参数的函数
the key and the value
关键和价值
so you can write a lambda expression
所以你可以写一个lambda表达式
that does that and it you know it's
那做到了，你知道那是
mostly a syntactic nicety but what it
主要是句法技巧，但它又是什么
does is it instead of you having to
就是这样，而不是您不必
iterate over the map entries and then do
遍历地图条目，然后执行
get key and get value it just hands you
获得关键并获得价值，这一切就交给您
the key and value separately so it's
键和值分别是
much more convenient in that way similar
这样更方便
to lists there's also a replace all on
列出还有一个替换所有
map and so again you can you can in Java
地图，因此您可以再次使用Java
7 you have to write a for loop over each
7你必须在每个上面写一个for循环
entry map entry has a set value method
条目映射条目具有设置值方法
so you can actually modify the the
因此您实际上可以修改
underlying entry in place but replace
基础条目到位，但替换
all does that for you and so the
一切都是为了你，所以
semantics here are this takes a lambda
这里的语义是lambda
that takes two arguments the key and the
它需要两个参数键和
value and the return value is the
值，返回值为
replacement value and so if we want to
重置价值，所以如果我们想
change all of them the values in the map
更改所有地图中的值
to uppercase we just write it here k v
大写我们只是在这里写
arrow and then call v dot to uppercase
箭头，然后将v点调用为大写
so this is kind of limited i mean if you
所以这是有限的，我的意思是如果你
want to do exactly this it's wonderful
想要做到这一点真是太好了
but it can only change the values in the
但它只能更改
map you can't change keys and you can't
地图，您不能更改键，也不能
change the types of either the key to
将任一键的类型更改为
the value so there are limitations there
值，所以那里有限制
if you want to do those things you have
如果你想做那些事
to go over to streams and stream over
越过溪流越过
the map entries and transform things
地图条目并进行转换
that way all right now here is kind of
这样一来，现在这里有点
an extended example and i'm going to set
一个扩展的例子，我要设置
this up by talking about multi maps
通过谈论多张地图
which many people are familiar with but
许多人都熟悉但
if you have a one of the things about a
如果您有一个关于
built-in map takes a has key value pairs
内置地图需要一个具有键值对的
but most importantly they're for every
但最重要的是，它们适合每个人
key there is exactly one value and in
键中只有一个值
many cases you might want to have a data
很多情况下，您可能需要数据
structure where you have a key that maps
您具有映射键的结构
to multiple values and so the various
多个值等等
libraries such as eclipse collections in
eclipse集合之类的库
guava have multi set excuse me multi map
番石榴有多套请问多地图
data structures built in JDK does not
JDK中内置的数据结构不
have one and sometimes if you can't use
有一个，有时如果你不能使用
one of those libraries what you have to
这些库之一，您必须
do is say okay I can't use a multi map
就是说我不能使用多地图
so instead I'll write out a map
所以我会写一张地图
up from say if I want a map from string
从说如果我想从字符串映射
to multiple integers I would have map
到多个整数我将有映射
from string to set of integers and just
从字符串到整数集，仅
store that in a regular hash map and in
将其存储在常规哈希图和
seven in Java 7 and earlier this can
Java 7和更早版本中的七个
actually get pretty painful so here's
实际上变得非常痛苦，所以这是
some code to do that if I want to put a
一些代码，如果我想放一个
value string string and an integer into
值字符串字符串和一个整数
my multi map then I first have to say ok
我的多张地图，那么我首先要说好
get the value for the key to see if
获取密钥的值以查看是否
there's a set already there if there
那里已经有一套了
isn't then I have to create a set and
不是，那么我必须创建一个集合
put it into the map and then finally
把它放进地图，然后最后
after that I have to add the new integer
之后，我必须添加新的整数
value into that set there's a similar
值中有一个相似的
thing for rule except kind of in Reverse
规则以外的东西
I ask you get the value corresponding to
我问你得到对应的值
this key and if it's non null then I go
这个键，如果它不是非null，那么我去
ahead and remove it from the set oh but
提前将其从集合中删除哦，但是
also if the set now became empty I want
另外，如果现在变得空了，我想要
to remove the whole thing and in fact
去掉整个东西，实际上
all right I'm out of room on the slide
好吧，我不在幻灯片上了
so it's already it's already the code is
所以已经是代码了
already too bulky so it turns out there
已经太庞大了，所以事实证明
are a bunch of new methods in Java 8
Java 8中有很多新方法
that make things like doing things like
使事情像做某事一样
this really easy so one of them is
这真的很容易，所以其中之一是
compute if absent what's interesting is
计算是否缺少有趣的是
that the the concurrent hash map prior
并发哈希映射之前
to Java 8 had some of these because you
Java 8之所以拥有这些功能，是因为您
really need atomic composite operations
确实需要原子复合操作
on concurrent on a concurrent map so
在并发映射上并发
these some of these have been promoted
这些中的一些已经被提升
to the main map interface in Java 8
Java 8中的主地图界面
anyway so compute if absent is an
无论如何，请计算是否缺少
interesting thing here what it does is
有趣的是，它的作用是
it evaluates the lambda expression that
它评估lambda表达式
you pass it if if the key is absent and
如果没有密钥，则通过它
then it takes the result of that and
然后它的结果和
stores it in the map and interestingly
将其存储在地图中，有趣的是
regardless of whether it actually did
不管它是否真的
that computation or not it returns the
该计算是否返回
value corresponding to the key so you
对应于键的值，这样您
have to pick through this a little bit
必须通过一点点
carefully but basically what this does
仔细但基本上这样做
is add the new hash set if it's absent
添加新的哈希集（如果不存在）
and then so so that we have a set valued
然后，使我们有一个设定值
multi map and so what the return from
多图等等从中得到什么
compute of absent is the set of integers
缺席的计算是整数集
and then we just go ahead and add it and
然后我们继续进行添加
so I'm not going to go through all of
所以我不会经历所有的
these in detail but you can kind of see
这些详细，但您可以看到
they have the same flavor remove is kind
他们有相同的味道
of the same way there's kind of
以同样的方式
complicated expression there but what
那里的表情很复杂，但是
remove can do is actually so there's
删除可以做的实际上是这样的
there's a there's a dual to compute if
有一个对偶要计算，如果
absent which is compute if present and
如果存在则不计算
what these can do is if the return value
这些可以做什么是如果返回值
is null and actually has the effect of
为null，实际上具有
removing a mapping from the map and so
从地图上删除地图，如此
if you run through a multi map style
如果您使用多地图样式
collection their usual map kind of
收集他们通常的地图种类
operations like I show put remove
像我显示的操作删除
contain size values and so forth
包含大小值等等
basically with the new default methods
基本上使用新的默认方法
on map all of these turn into one-liners
在地图上所有这些都变成了单线
and so if you don't need to have a full
所以如果你不需要一个完整的
multi map implementation and most
多地图实施和大多数
applications don't maybe you just put a
应用程序也许你不只是放一个
bunch of stuff in and then say okay I
一堆东​​西然后说好吧我
want to you know I want to I want to
想要你知道我想要我想要
deal with these particular cases you can
处理这些特殊情况，您可以
you can kind of get the effect of your
你可以得到你的效果
own multi map just by implementing a few
通过实施一些自己的多地图
of these one-liners so in fact this
这些单线的，所以实际上
isn't even the half of it so I show
还不到一半，所以我展示
computer if absent computer present and
计算机（如果没有），并且
get our default which are new methods
得到我们的默认值是新方法
new default methods on map there are I
地图上有新的默认方法
think there's well I'm not even going to
认为我什至不去
go through them all they're a bunch more
经历他们，他们都是一堆
and what you have to do is go through
而你要做的就是经历
the Java doc and look for things things
Java文档并查找事物
on the map interface that are since
在地图界面上
since 1.8 but anyway I think these are
从1.8开始，但无论如何我认为这些是
the most interesting ones here all right
这里最有趣的
so there's another interface that we
所以我们还有另一个界面
spent a lot of time on in Java 8 which
在Java 8上花了很多时间
is comparator now comparators are in
是比较器，现在比较器在
their simplest form are pretty easy but
他们最简单的形式很容易，但是
when they get complicated they get
当他们变得复杂时，他们会得到
really complicated and error-prone and I
我真的很复杂而且容易出错
think there's there's a whole other talk
认为那里还有其他话题
to be done about comparators themselves
关于比较器本身
but what we did in Java 8 was add a
但是我们在Java 8中所做的是添加了一个
bunch of helper methods or combinators
一堆辅助方法或组合器
which take which which construct simple
哪个结构简单
comparators for you and then also come
比较器，然后你也来
comparators to return to create new
比较器返回以创建新的
comparators that give more complex and
比较器提供更复杂的
interesting behavior and so what that
有趣的行为等等
should allow you to do and it's not
应该让你做，不是
quite there yet but probably in a large
在那里，但可能很大
fraction of cases what these new methods
这些新方法所占的比例很小
allow you to do is take a bunch of hand
允许你做的就是牵一手
coded open logic and compress it into
编码开放逻辑并将其压缩成
function essentially successive calls to
功能基本上是连续调用
these comparator methods that provide
这些比较器方法提供
that provide composite functionality and
提供复合功能
make things much neater alright so I'm
让事情变得更加整洁，所以我
going to run through a quick example
通过一个简单的例子
here which is a two-level sort so
这里是两级排序
suppose you have is it a person class no
假设你有一个人班
student class or something like that
学生课之类的
just say student has a last name and
只是说学生有姓，
first name so I want to do the first
名，所以我想做第一个
level sort on the students last name and
对学生的姓氏进行等级排序，然后
then for students that have the same
然后对于那些具有相同
last name I want to do a second level
我想做第二个名字
sort on the first name but there's also
按名字排序，但也有
a catch because maybe we don't have the
一个渔获物，因为也许我们没有
maybe we don't have a first name for all
也许我们没有所有人的名字
the students and the first name might be
学生和名字可能是
null so if the students first name is
null，因此，如果学生的名字是
null then those should sort before
null，那么这些应该在之前排序
before all other students that have a
在所有其他具有
non null first name all right so let's
非null名可以，所以让我们
look at what you have to do in Java 7 to
看看您在Java 7中要做的
do that I'm not going to pick through
这样做我不会接手
all this code but you can kind of
所有这些代码，但您可以
eyeball it and say ok we get the last
盯着它说好吧，我们得到了最后一个
name you compare it and then alright so
给你起个名字，然后比较
so if the last names are equal then and
因此，如果姓氏相等，则和
get the first names then we do null test
得到名字然后我们做空测试
and then you know there's a little bit
然后你知道有一点
of dancing around here and I'm pretty
在这里跳舞的感觉，我很漂亮
sure this code is correct but I'm not
确保此代码正确，但我不正确
entirely sure you could pick through it
完全确定您可以选择
and in fact if I introduced the bug then
实际上，如果我介绍了该错误，
it would be really hard to see that
真的很难看到
there actually was a bug because there's
实际上有一个错误，因为有
lots of lots of little conditionals in
很多很多小条件
here lots of little details if you swap
如果您交换，这里有很多小细节
a one and a minus one in the wrong place
一个错误的地方和一个错误的地方
you know boy it's really hard to it's
你知道男孩真的很难
really hard to determine that by
真的很难确定
inspection
检查
unless what you do is you go out and get
除非你做的就是你出去得到
some sample data and pick through it or
一些样本数据并进行选择或
step through it any bug or something
逐步解决任何错误或其他问题
like that so this stuff writing this
这样的东西写这个
kind of stuff is really error-prone
东西真的很容易出错
and I see a lot of questions on Stack
我在Stack上看到很多问题
Overflow and forums about what's wrong
溢出和论坛出了什么问题
with my comparator and so forth and it's
和我的比较器等等
not surprising because this is really
不足为奇，因为这真的
it's really detailed and if you don't
它真的很详细，如果您不
get it exactly right you have a subtle
完全正确，你有一个微妙的地方
bug that that can creep in alright so in
可以蔓延的错误
Java 8 alright so this is this is a
Java 8好的，这是一个
little bit of a refactoring so instead
一点重构，所以
of calling collection stop sort we call
呼叫收集停止排序的过程
students thought sort and instead of
学生认为排序而不是
using an anonymous inner class we
使用匿名内部类，我们
convert it to a lambda and you know that
转换成lambda，你知道
helps by you know 10% right so we got
可以帮助您知道10％正确，所以我们得到了
rid of a line or to a boilerplate code
摆脱线条或样板代码
but basically that bulk of custom logic
但基本上是大量的自定义逻辑
inside the comparator itself is the same
比较器内部本身是相同的
and it suffers from all the same
而且遭受同样的痛苦
problems and unfortunately I don't have
问题，不幸的是我没有
time to go through this in detail but
是时候详细介绍了，但是
you'll have to believe me that this code
您必须相信我，这段代码
is the equivalent of the code on the
是等价于
previous slide and so what we do is
上一张幻灯片，所以我们要做的是
there's a there's a new method called
有一种叫做
comparator dot comparing and it takes
比较器点比较，它需要
what we call a key extractor so in this
我们称之为密钥提取器
case it's get last name it's just a
如果是姓氏，那只是一个
function or just a method that gets a
函数或只是获得
field out of out of your object but
超出你的目标
what's interesting is a typical Parador
有趣的是典型的Parador
is highly stylized code I want to get
是我想要获得的高度程式化的代码
the field from this object I want to get
我要获取的对象的字段
the field from this object and then
该对象的字段，然后
compare them and so instead of writing
比较它们，所以不用写
that out by hand comparative comparator
手工比较出来的
dot comparing does that for you and so
点比较为您做到了，所以
you just say which field you want I want
你只说我想要哪个领域
to get the last name ok boom there's a
要获得好名字，可以有一个
comparator that compares last name
比较姓氏的比较器
there's another method on comparator
比较器上还有另一种方法
called
叫
then comparing and so if I have five a
然后比较，所以如果我有五个
comparator and this first comparator the
比较器和第一个比较器
result of this calling the first
第一次调用的结果
comparator is that the values are equal
比较器是值相等
then I want to apply a second-level sort
然后我想应用二级排序
and that's what then comparing does so
那就是比较的结果
it takes two comparators and smashes
它需要两个比较器并粉碎
them together in this particular way to
他们以这种特殊的方式在一起
give you a two-level sort so instead of
给您一个两级排序，而不是
having a bunch of conditional logic that
有很多条件逻辑
does that for you it it allows you to
为您做到这一点，它可以让您
build up this composite comparator from
从中建立这个复合比较器
smaller comparators
较小的比较器
and then Noel's first is kind of the
然后Noel首先是
same thing so generally we want to do a
同样的事情，所以通常我们想做一个
string comparison but what if the string
字符串比较，但是如果字符串
is null well you're going to get a null
为null，那么您将获得null
pointer exception
指针异常
well nulls first is another utility
那么null首先是另一个实用程序
method that says okay I'm going to do a
好的方法，我要去做
comparison and I want to sort nulls
比较，我想对null进行排序
first so it sets those aside and then
首先将其放在一边，然后
for non null things it just calls the
对于非null的东西，它只是调用
calls the regular comparator so again
再次调用常规比较器
the flavor here is that we're building
这里的味道是我们正在建立
up a complex comparator with lots of
建立一个复杂的比较器
weird conditionals and stuff that you
奇怪的条件和东西，你
saw on the previous slide by composing
在上一张幻灯片上看到了
little bits of pieces so we start with a
一点点的碎片，所以我们从一个
natural order we we sort the nulls first
自然顺序，我们首先对空值进行排序
and we then we're sorting the results of
然后我们对结果进行排序
first name on that and that's the
关于这个的名字就是
second-level comparison within the
二级比较
first-level comparison of get last name
获得姓氏的第一级比较
so there's a lot of stuff going on in
所以里面有很多东西
this code that that saves you the effort
节省您精力的这段代码
of writing all the complicated
写所有复杂的
conditional logic on the previous slide
上一张幻灯片中的条件逻辑
I should have put up this slide because
我应该放这张幻灯片，因为
this sort of explains it here but anyway
这种解释在这里，但无论如何
that this basically says what I what I
那基本上就是说我在说什么
just tried to explain and so I'll make
只是试图解释，所以我会做
sure this slide that gets posted and so
确保这张幻灯片被张贴等等
you can take a closer look at this
你可以仔细看看
afterwards all right so after this now
之后没事了，所以在此之后
that's the end of the Java 8 segment and
到Java 8段的结尾，
I can start talking about Java 9 now all
我现在可以开始谈论Java 9
right
对
ok so what the the little bit of history
好吧，那一点点的历史
of of what went into Java 9 there have
Java 9中有
been a couple efforts over the years in
这些年来，我们付出了很多努力
Java to add collection literals these
Java添加集合文字
have always been proposed as language
一直被提议为语言
enhancements in Java 7 there was project
Java 7中的增强功能有一个项目
coin and one of the proposals that was
硬币和其中一项提案
entertained was to add collection
招待是要添加收藏
literals and some proposals were floated
文字和一些建议被提出
around but that that never went anywhere
周围，​​但那从未到过
after Java 8 there was a JEP JDK
Java 8之后，有了一个JEP JDK
enhancement proposal it was a little odd
增强建议有点奇怪
it was a research jet but basically the
这是一架研究喷气机，但基本上
idea was to was to scope out what was
想法是要确定什么是
required to add collection literals to
需要将集合文字添加到
the language and the
语言和
result of that was a decision that we
结果是我们的决定
would not add collection literals to the
不会将集合文字添加到
language and it's it's I think the the
语言，这是我认为
most succinct way to explain that
最简洁的解释方式
decision is to observe that unlike many
决定是要观察到
other languages and systems Java has has
Java拥有的其他语言和系统
clearly defined architecture where the
明确定义的架构
JVM is separate from the java
JVM与Java分开
programming language and the programming
编程语言和编程
language is in turn separate from the
语言又与
libraries and collections are a library
图书馆和馆藏是图书馆
construct and so if you mix the idea of
构建，所以如果您混合考虑
collections too closely into the
收集太紧密了
programming language itself then things
编程语言本身然后是事物
get to be very uncomfortable so the
变得非常不舒服，所以
question is suppose so as we have a
问题是假设的，因为我们有一个
programming language syntax that creates
创建的编程语言语法
a list okay well what what lists your
列表好吧，什么列出了您的
that Beach should that be ArrayList well
那海滩应该是ArrayList好
ArrayList is fine for many things but
ArrayList对于很多事情都可以，但是
suppose I wanted it be mutable suppose I
假设我希望它是可变的假设我
wanted it to be sparse or suppose I want
希望它稀疏或假设我想要
it to be something else and so it
变成别的东西，所以
wouldn't be too difficult to do
不会太难做
something simplistic in the language but
语言上有些简单化，但
then that would bind too tightly to
那会太紧密地绑定到
particular implementations in the
中的特定实现
library and so if we didn't want that
图书馆，所以如果我们不想那样
tight binding then we'd have to design a
紧密绑定，那么我们必须设计一个
programming language that that somehow
以某种方式编程的语言
had a looser coupling with the library
与图书馆的联系更加宽松
maybe ended up calling collections
也许最终打电话给收藏
builders or something but basically
建设者之类的东西，但基本上
since the language and the library are
因为语言和图书馆是
are architectural II distinct building
是二号建筑
something like collection literals
像集合文字
across that turns out to be great amount
事实证明这是一个很大的数目
of effort if we want to preserve the
如果我们想保留
flexibility of keeping the collections
保存收藏的灵活性
framework at arm's length from the
框架距离
programming language so anyway so the
所以无论如何编程语言
upshot of that is we decided not to add
结果是我们决定不添加
collection literals to the language and
语言的集合文字和
instead what we said was let's add some
相反，我们说的是让我们添加一些
convenience api's to the existing
现有的便捷api
collections framework and that will get
收藏框架，这将得到
us probably 80% of the benefit of
我们大概有80％的收益
of collection literals but it's much
集合字面量，但很多
much simpler to do right it's a library
做起来要简单得多，这是一个图书馆
only construct so it's just AP is we
唯一的构造，所以只有AP是我们
didn't have to we didn't have to make
不必我们不必做
any changes to the the JVM or the
对JVM或
programming language or the compiler or
编程语言或编译器或
anything they're just they're just new
他们只是他们的新事物
library api's and they're pretty useful
库API，它们非常有用
there are a few cases where it would be
在某些情况下
nice to have language support for it but
很高兴为此提供语言支持，但
I'll talk about those in a minute but
我一会儿再谈
otherwise I think it came out pretty
否则我觉得它挺漂亮的
well and they're quite useful and I
好，它们非常有用，我
think you'll you'll like them
想你会喜欢他们
alright so the design goals for the
好了，所以设计目标
basically so their convenience api's and
基本上，所以他们的便捷API和
basically they are all static factory
基本上都是静态工厂
methods so we are adding methods to
方法，所以我们要添加方法
static methods to the interfaces to
接口的静态方法
produce collections collections
产生收藏
instances so the main goals of these new
实例，所以这些新的主要目标
api's are convenience and brevity to be
api既方便又简洁
as close as possible to collection
尽可能接近收藏
literals as possible but we wanted them
尽可能多的文字，但我们想要它们
to be space efficient you can gain some
为了节省空间，您可以获得一些
space efficiency if you have an
如果您有空间效率
immutable collection since it doesn't
不可变的集合，因为它不会
need to be modified you can pack things
需要修改就可以打包东西
in in a different way and save a lot of
以不同的方式保存很多
space and also the the collections
空间以及收藏
instances returned are actually
返回的实例实际上是
immutable which is kind of a new thing
不变的，这是新事物
in in the JDK all right so anyway so JDK
在JDK中可以正常使用，所以JDK
9 is work in progress
9正在进行中
this work was integrated quite some time
这项工作已经整合了很长时间
ago so any any recent build of JDK 9
以前是这样，所以任何最近的JDK 9构建
will have these in it and so I encourage
里面有这些，所以我鼓励
you to download JDK 9 and try them out
您下载JDK 9并试用
but the interesting thing about this is
但是有趣的是
this on it on its surface adding these
在其表面上添加这些
API is like well gee you know with an
API就像您知道的
hour's thought you could write out a
一个小时的思想，你可以写出一个
bunch of write out the api's and
一堆写出的api和
implementations and I think I did so in
实现，我想我是这样做的
fact I did so several times but what was
事实上我做了几次，但是
what was interesting was that there a
有趣的是
surprising number of issues lurking
潜伏的问题数量惊人
under the surface and design decisions
根据表面和设计决策
that we had to go through so that's
我们必须经历的是
that's what the rest of this talk is
这就是剩下的话题
about so quickly here is the overview of
大约这么快，这里是
the new API is in JDK 9 so there is a
新的API在JDK 9中，因此
list of
清单
taking zero one two actually up to ten
取零一二实际上最多十
arguments and then list out of taking
参数然后列出来
varargs so that will create a list with
varargs，以便使用
however many elements you pass
无论您传递多少元素
there's set of which is the same thing
这是一组相同的东西
there's also map thought of and math is
还有地图的思想和数学是
different because it doesn't doesn't
不同，因为它没有
take elements of a single type instead
取一个单一类型的元素代替
it has to take key value pairs so for a
它必须采用键值对，因此对于
fixed number for a small number of key
固定数量的小钥匙
value pairs we pass alternating keys and
值对，我们传递交替键和
values but if you want more more than
值，但如果您想要的不只是
and there's no way to do a varargs for
而且没有办法为
that so if you want more that we've
所以，如果您想要更多我们
added a new method map dot of entries
添加了新的方法映射条目点
alright so for efficiency reasons so
好吧，出于效率考虑，所以
this is a snapshot of the Javadoc for
这是Javadoc的快照
the the map interface so for efficiency
地图界面，以便提高效率
reasons we've provided zero through ten
我们提供零到十的原因
over six tardes
超过六个
because varargs unavoidably has an
因为varargs不可避免地具有
overhead of constructing and copying
构建和复制的开销
elements into an array and so in order
元素排列成一个数组
to avoid avoid that we provide six dog
为了避免避免我们提供六只狗
overloads and so I don't know how many
超载，所以我不知道有多少
of you were here at the opening keynote
你们中的一些人在开幕式上
when chet haase gave his you know
切特·海瑟给他你知道的时候
technology business talk I thought he
我以为他谈技术生意
was pretty funny
很有趣
I would like to be as funny as chat was
我想像聊天一样有趣
but I'm still working on it but I think
但我仍在努力，但我认为
I have potential because when I posted
我有潜力，因为当我发布
this API to read it somebody said is
有人说的这个API是
this a joke so anyway here are some
这是个玩笑，反正这是一些
examples of the new API is in action in
新API的示例正在
Java 8 actually this is kind of three
Java 8实际上这是三种
examples glom together
例子在一起
there's list set and map and so if you
有列表集和地图，所以如果您
needed to create a list arrays out as
需要创建一个列表数组作为
list isn't too bad if you need to create
如果您需要创建列表，还不错
a hash set containing specific things
包含特定内容的哈希集
well the easiest thing was to create a
最简单的事情是创建一个
list and then put it into a hash set and
列表，然后将其放入哈希集，然后
then map I think is the worst you have
那我认为地图是最糟糕的
to create a map and then call put
创建地图，然后调用put
successively into it and on the bottom
先后进入它并在底部
you can see Java and I mean say list of
您可以看到Java，我的意思是说
set of and math autos and it's all right
套和数学汽车，这没关系
there and it's pretty nice so so
那里很好，所以
now so there's a variation here which is
现在，这里有一个变化是
if you wanted to to create a map with an
如果您想使用
arbitrary number of pairs then you have
任意数量的对，那么你有
to switch over to this map dot of
切换到该地图的
entries method which takes a varargs
带可变参数的entrys方法
varargs parameter of map entries and so
映射条目的varargs参数等等
creating a map entry is kind of can be
创建一个地图条目是可以的
kind of complicated because there's
有点复杂，因为
there's a map the the most common
有一张最常见的地图
implementation of map entry is abstract
地图条目的实现是抽象的
map sought simple immutable entry which
地图寻求简单的不可变条目，
is quite a mouthful so so one of the
足够一口，所以其中之一
other things that this adds is a static
这增加的其他内容是静态的
factory method called math dot entry
工厂方法称为数学点输入
lower case entry that just takes two
只需要两个的小写条目
arguments a key and a value and returns
给一个键和一个值做参数并返回
a map entry instance and so here's an
地图条目实例，所以这是一个
example of that because this exceeds the
的例子，因为这超出了
number the six starred variation the
编号六个加星标的变体
fixed arg overloads of mapped of so we
修复了映射的arg超载，因此我们
have to we have to use map dot of
必须要使用的地图点
entries and then pass it you know a
条目，然后通过它，您知道一个
succession of entry objects all right so
入口对象的继承可以
they're a bunch of design and
他们是一堆设计，
implementation issues that I alluded to
我提到的实施问题
earlier and so I'm going to step through
较早，所以我要逐步
these pretty quickly here and the time
这些在这里和时间都很快
remaining so handling handling an
剩下的，所以处理
arbitrary number of mappings is what I
我是任意数量的映射
just what I just talked about we ended
我刚才所说的我们就结束了
up at that solution after considering
在考虑了该解决方案之后
about fifteen other alternatives I
我约有十五种其他选择
should I should write those up sometime
我应该在某个时候写下来吗
those are those are interesting they all
这些都是有趣的
have pros and cons but but when you have
有优点和缺点，但是当你有
when you're faced with a lot of choices
当您面临很多选择时
you can't just look at and say I like
你不能只是看着说我喜欢
this one better than that one so I
这个比那个更好，所以我
actually did come up with a set of
实际上确实提出了一套
criteria for what what I wanted out of
我想要什么的标准
this API and so obviously simpler is
这个API，因此显然更简单的是
better less boilerplate but an
最好少样板，但
interesting one is the API should be a
有趣的是，API应该是
compile time type safe so some of the
编译时间类型安全，因此一些
alternatives and some of the
替代品和一些
alternatives that people proposed if you
人们提出的替代方案，如果您
have keys and values of of different
具有不同的键和值
types then the most common super-tight
然后是最常见的超紧类型
might be object and so how do you and
可能是对象，所以您和
and you you can't have a VAR args that
而且你不能有一个VAR参数
has different types and so some people
有不同的类型，所以有些人
said oh just take a VAR args of object
说哦，只需要对象的VAR参数
and you know yeah we'll deal with type
你知道的，我们会处理类型
of
的
safety that's okay it's like wow I don't
安全没关系，就像哇，我不知道
think so job is very very much very much
认为工作非常非常非常
focused on static static type checking
专注于静态静态类型检查
and compile time so having arguments
并编译时间，以便有参数
that are not checked at compile time is
在编译时未检查的是
is kind of a dodgy thing to do so
这样做是一种狡猾的事情
another thing is we wanted the number of
另一件事是我们想要的数量
elements to be known at compile time and
在编译时已知的元素，以及
so you can have a you know an
所以你可以拥有一个你知道的
alternative was to have a builder so you
替代方案是有一个建筑商，所以你
just call build you know add add add add
只是调用构建，您知道添加添加添加添加
add or something like that and the
添加或类似的东西和
problem there is you have to in the
问题是你必须在
process of building you have to
建立过程中，您必须
accumulate those and that could involve
积累那些可能涉及
successive reallocations and copies
连续重新分配和副本
because you don't know how many times
因为你不知道多少次
the guy is going to add entries before
这个家伙要在之前添加条目
building the final map and so what we
建立最终的地图，等等
wanted to do is again at compile time
想做的还是在编译时
have the size be statically known or at
具有静态已知的大小或
least not statically known but known at
至少不是静态已知的，但已知于
the initial entry and so varargs does
初始条目，所以varargs这样做
have that because when you receive a VAR
之所以这样，是因为当您收到VAR时
x parameter you get an array of a fixed
x参数得到一个固定的数组
size and so you know that that that's
大小，所以你知道那是
the number of elements you have so
你拥有的元素数量
another common one somebody said oh just
另一个普通人说哦
have just have two two arrays of
只有两个两个数组
different things and and that's that's
不同的东西，那就是
fine two arrays at different types an
对不同类型的两个数组进行精细处理
array of keys an array of values and and
键数组值数组和
that's fine that's fine that kind of
没关系没关系
works you have to do some cross checking
工作，你必须做一些交叉检查
to make sure that the arrays are the
确保数组是
same size but when you write out code
大小相同，但写出代码时
that does that then the keys and the
那然后是键和
values unless you contort your source
值，除非您扭曲来源
code in a very strange way your keys are
以非常奇怪的方式编写代码
going to be very far away from your the
会离你的很远
corresponding values and so it's like
相应的值，就像
yes you can do that functionally in the
是的，您可以在功能上
API but we need write source code it's
API，但我们需要编写源代码
just not going to work so anyway and
只是不去上班所以反正
then ideally we would like to avoid
那么理想情况下，我们希望避免
boxing where possible and it turns out
尽可能地装箱，结果
that we were able to satisfy all of
我们能够满足所有
those accept accept boxing so I went
那些接受拳击所以我去了
over this already there's a new
在这已经有一个新的
convenience method called entry which
方便的方法称为进入
takes a key and a value you can pass a
需要一个键和一个值，您可以传递一个
succession of those to the map dot of
那些到的地图点的继承
entries method so that's what we we
条目方法，这就是我们
ended up with it's not perfect it's a
最终不完美，这是一个
little bit more verbose than I would
比我更冗长
like
喜欢
but I think it does satisfy most of the
但我认为它确实满足了大多数
criteria and it works well all right so
标准，并且效果很好，所以
here's something here's something fairly
这是一些东西
new in the Java world which is immutable
Java世界中的新特性是不可变的
data structures and so the the instances
数据结构以及实例
returned by these new methods are
这些新方法返回的是
immutable which means that you cannot
一成不变的，这意味着你不能
modify them so I want to stress that
修改它们，以便我强调
this is what I guess what we call
我想这就是我们所说的
conventional immutability so it's just
传统的不变性
like a regular Java collection it's just
就像常规的Java集合一样
that if you call a mutator method like
如果您调用类似mutator的方法
add or put then that is rejected with an
加或放然后被拒绝
unsupported operation exception I want
我想要的不受支持的操作异常
to contrast that with other libraries
与其他图书馆形成对比
and other language systems that have
和其他具有
persistent or immutable persistent data
持久或不变的持久数据
structures where you can sort of modify
您可以在其中进行修改的结构
the data structure but what you get is a
数据结构，但您得到的是
new data structure that has sharing with
与之共享的新数据结构
you old one that is not what this is
你那不是这个的老
this is kind of conventional
这是一种常规
immutability anyway this is good because
无论如何，这是好的，因为
there are a lot of cases where people
在很多情况下，人们
could use immutable data structures if
如果可以使用不可变的数据结构
they had them in Java and so the very
他们有Java语言的
common case to initialize a table of
初始化表的常见情况
things or list or something at the at
事物或清单或事物在
the beginning of a program and never
程序的开始，永不
change it for the lifetime of the
在整个生命周期内进行更改
program and so you don't want those
程序，所以你不想要那些
accidentally being changed and if
意外更改，如果
there's a space efficient way to store
有一种节省空间的方式来存储
them then you want to do that because
他们那么你想这样做，因为
you know if you know that the destructor
你知道你是否知道破坏者
is never going to be changed then why
永远不会改变，那为什么
pay a space penalty for the flexibility
为灵活性付出空间代价
of potentially modifying the data if
修改数据的可能性
you're never going to do that so there
你永远不会那样做，所以那里
were they're there historically have
他们在历史上有吗
been unmodifiable wrappers in the
被包装中不可修改的包装
collections framework and that's kind of
收藏框架，这有点
the closest thing to general-purpose
最接近通用的东西
immutability that was there up until now
到现在为止的不变性
so what you had to do is create a
所以你要做的就是创建一个
mutable data structure populate it and
可变数据结构填充其中，
then wrap it in an unmodified alrea
然后将其包裹在未修改的区域中
oh and then throw away the reference to
哦，然后扔掉对
the underlying one and that sort of
底层的那种
gives you immunity mutability as long as
只要您具有免疫变异性
you remember to throw away the
你记得扔掉
underlying reference but unmodifiable is
基本参考但不可修改的是
actually a different concept so in the
实际上是一个不同的概念
idea the unmodifiable wrap
想到不可修改的包装
is that they are views onto another
是他们对另一个的看法
collection that are that do not permit
不允许的集合
modification but if you still have a
修改，但如果您仍有
handle on the underlying collection then
然后处理基础集合
you can modify that so so even so if you
您可以进行修改，即使您
if you call into somewhere and it gives
如果你打电话到某个地方，它给
you a nun modifiable view that means you
您一个修女可修改的观点，这意味着您
can't modify it but you cannot trust
无法修改，但您无法信任
that it will never change
它将永远不会改变
so because somebody else might be
所以因为其他人可能是
modifying it so this idea of
修改它，这样的想法
unmodifiable that already exists in the
不可修改的
collections framework really is
收藏框架真的是
different from immutability and so these
与不变性不同，因此这些
collections cannot be modified unless
除非修改集合，否则除非
you go in like with reflection or unsafe
你像反射或不安全地进入
or something like that there are no
或类似的东西
api's that modify these collections
修改这些集合的api
alright so here is here's an interesting
好吧，这是一个有趣的地方
wrinkle that bears some explanation the
皱纹有一些解释
iteration order of the hashed set and
哈希集的迭代顺序和
map implementations that are that are
映射的实现是
returned by the new collection factories
新的回收工厂返回
the iteration order is randomized and it
迭代顺序是随机的，它
literally is randomized now if you look
如果您看一下，现在字面上是随机的
at sets and maps in the existing
在现有的布景和地图上
collection framework then there's some
收集框架，然后有一些
words in there about the iteration order
关于迭代顺序的单词
is unspecified but historically the
未指定，但历史上
iteration order has been pretty stable
迭代顺序非常稳定
so from from if you iterate over the
所以从如果您遍历
same collection multiple times it will
同一集合将多次
be in the same order
顺序相同
even from run to run or even from JDK
甚至从运行到运行，甚至从JDK运行
release to JDK release if you put the
如果您将
same elements into a hash map or hash
将相同的元素放入哈希映射或哈希
set they'll probably come out in the
设置他们可能会出现在
same order and the problem is that a lot
相同的顺序，问题是很多
of code grows to depend on very stable
的代码越来越依赖非常稳定的
iteration order and from time to time
迭代顺序和时间
something will happen that will change
将会发生改变的事情
the iteration order like if your program
迭代顺序就像您的程序一样
gets different input it might cause the
获得不同的输入，可能会导致
hash set to the half of the hash set or
散列集为散列集的一半，或
hash map to rehash everything and then
哈希映射以重新哈希所有内容，然后
things will come out in a different
事情会以不同的方式出现
order and your program will break or in
订单，您的程序将中断或进入
the JDK sometimes we've had to make some
JDK有时我们不得不做一些
performance enhancements or some
性能增强或某些
security vulnerabilities or something
安全漏洞或其他
where we would change the iteration
我们将在哪里更改迭代
order of a hash map and people yell at
哈希图的顺序和人们大吼
us a lot when you did that because you
我们这样做的时候很多，因为
broke our code it's like
破坏了我们的代码就像
well you know we come back with a finger
好吧，你知道我们用手指回来
right yeah you're not supposed to just
是的，你不应该只是
hand on the iteration or but but we
进行迭代或，但是我们
can't we can't take that line too hard
难道我们不能太过分
because when we change the iteration of
因为当我们改变迭代
hashmap our own code breaks right and so
哈希图，我们自己的代码正确，所以
what happens is it's like oh where's the
发生什么了，就像在哪里
where's the dependent interdependent in
相依相依在哪里
ordered pendency in this code I don't
我没有在此代码中命令下垂
know where it is just just change it to
知道它在哪里，只是将其更改为
a linked hash map that will give us
一个链接的哈希图，这将给我们
stable iteration order and then the
稳定迭代顺序，然后
problems go away and it's like ah so
问题消失了，就像啊，所以
that's that's really uncomfortable but
那真的很不舒服，但是
the fact is we have the worst of prior
事实是我们有最坏的经历
to Java 9 we have the worst of both
到Java 9，我们两者都有
worlds we have iteration order that is
世界，我们有迭代顺序是
unspecified but that is stable enough to
未指定，但足够稳定
low people into thinking that that it
低级的人认为
actually is stable and then when it
实际上是稳定的，然后当它
changes
变化
lots of stuff breaks so the solution to
很多东西中断了，所以解决方案
that for the new collections only is
对于新的收藏是
that the iteration order is randomized
迭代顺序是随机的
so what happens is that the @vm launch
所以发生的是@vm启动
basically gets a random random number
基本上得到一个随机的随机数
which is XOR it into the internet hash
将它异或到互联网哈希中
code and so the effect is that from one
代码，所以效果是
run of the JVM to the next the iteration
JVM运行到下一个迭代
order of the set and maps returned by
集的顺序和返回的地图
the new factories the iteration order
新工厂的迭代顺序
will change from one JVM run to the next
将从一个JVM运行更改为另一个
and so the hope is that this will flush
所以希望这会冲洗
out any any code that has latent
排除任何潜在的代码
dependencies on iteration order and that
对迭代顺序的依赖以及
those problems will be flushed out
这些问题将被清除
during development and testing and so
在开发和测试期间等等
that they they won't come out in
他们他们不会出来
production but also actually it's also
生产，但实际上它也是
buying ourselves some flexibility here
在这里购买一些灵活性
which is we may want to go in and
我们可能想要进入
reorganize the internals of of the way
重组内部方式
that entries are stored in these maps or
条目存储在这些映射中，或者
sets and we want the freedom to be able
设置，我们希望自由能够
to do that and get you you know better
做到这一点，让您更了解
you know better performance better space
你知道更好的性能更好的空间
efficiency and so forth without having
效率等
to worry about preserving iteration
担心保留迭代
order so that's one of the toughest
订单，这是最难的一项
things if if you have to preserve
如果必须保存的话
iteration order that's a cost that needs
迭代顺序是需要的成本
to be paid even if it's not actually
即使不是实际要支付
specified and so we wanted to avoid that
指定，所以我们想避免这种情况
so again this applies only to the new
再次，这仅适用于新
collections
馆藏
returned by the new collections factory
新馆工厂归还
methods the existing collections you
方法现有的集合
know those are going to stay the same I
知道那些将保持不变我
think adding randomized iteration of
认为添加随机迭代
those randomized iteration order to the
那些对
existing collections is is not something
现有的收藏不是什么
that certainly not something we're going
当然不是我们要去的东西
to do by default maybe there would be an
默认情况下可能会
opt-in thing for for debugging purposes
出于调试目的选择加入的东西
but nothing more than that
但仅此而已
okay another characteristic of the new
好吧，新的另一个特点
collections is that nulls are disallowed
集合是不允许空值
so I think in retrospect the new
所以我回想一下新的
collections introduced sorry but when
收藏集介绍很抱歉，但是当
the collections framework was originally
收集框架最初是
introduced back in one point to the main
一站式介绍到主要
collections did allow nulls and in
集合确实允许null和in
retrospect that's that's been regarded
回顾那已经被认为
as a mistake nothing recent has allowed
作为错误，最近没有允许
allowed nulls in particular the concur
允许null尤其是同意
none of the concurrent collections allow
并发集合均不允许
null entries and the reason they're a
空条目及其原因
couple reasons that one is null shows up
显示为null的几个原因
in special kit in special places in the
在特殊套件中的特殊位置
api's so there's the case of math get if
api的，所以有数学的情况下，如果
that returns null does that mean the
返回null意味着
entry is absent or does it mean the
条目不存在或是否意味着
entry was present but its value is null
条目存在，但其值为空
so you have to you have to do something
所以你必须要做些什么
else to disambiguate but there also some
其他要消除歧义，但也有一些
things in the especially in concurrent
特别是在并发中
collections the like map dot compute
收集类似地图点计算
like I mentioned before if if your
就像我之前提到的，如果
lambda expression returns null that has
lambda表达式返回具有以下内容的null
the effect of removing the entry as
删除条目的效果为
opposed to storing a null into the map
反对将空值存储到地图中
and so null is is very important special
所以null是非常重要的特殊
case that's useful for AP is in that way
对AP有用的情况就是这样
also it's really useful to have nulls
还有null真的很有用
inside the collection as special
里面的收藏很特别
sentinels and so it makes you know if
哨兵，所以它让你知道
you actually look at what the what
你实际上在看什么
things like hash map the the regular old
像哈希映射之类的东西
java.util hash map has to have a bunch
java.util哈希映射必须有一堆
of special cases in case somebody wants
万一有人想要的特殊情况
to store a null in the hash maps because
在哈希图中存储null
by default null means there's nothing
默认情况下，null表示没有任何内容
there and so so there's special cases
在那里，所以有特殊情况
sprinkled throughout the code and it
散布在整个代码中
just just makes things more complicated
只是使事情变得更复杂
in error-prone alright so another
容易出错，所以另一个
another wrinkle here is that
这里的另一个皱纹是
when you're populating a set arm map it
当您填充手臂图时
throws exceptions on duplicate entries
对重复的条目抛出异常
and there's a bit of rationale here I
我这里有些道理
think I need to move on a little more
认为我需要继续前进
quickly but if you have a big table like
很快，但是如果您有一张大桌子
this here's an example there's a there's
这是一个例子，那里有一个
a duplicate entry in here and I think
我在这里有一个重复的条目
either you know most most systems use
要么您知道大多数系统都在使用
last one wins which means that if you
最后一个获胜，这意味着如果您
put this if you compile this into your
如果您将其编译到您的
program you would actually have one
程序你实际上会有一个
fewer entry than you expected and you'd
少于您预期的条目，并且您会
have some weird behavior runtime but if
有一些奇怪的行为运行时，但是如果
you actually put this into Java 9 and
您实际上将其放入Java 9中
we'll throw in a legal argument
我们将提出法律依据
exception and say that well hey this is
例外，说好吧，这是
a duplicate entry and so the point here
重复的条目，所以这里的重点
is that this is a this is a library API
这是一个库API
that is modeling collection literals and
这是建模集合文字和
so if you have a collection literal that
因此，如果您有一个集合文字
means you're writing out all the values
表示您正在写出所有值
and so if you put in duplicates that's
因此，如果您重复输入
probably an error I'm very sorry about
可能是一个错误，我很抱歉
this I'm running short on time so I have
我时间不多了，所以我有
a bunch of stuff to say about space
一堆关于空间的东西
efficiency but really the existing I
效率，但实际上是现有的我
just want to say very briefly the
只想很简单地说
existing collections especially things
现有的收藏，特别是东西
like hash that are pretty space
像哈希一样漂亮的空间
inefficient they use lots of objects and
效率低下，他们使用很多对象，
lots of pointers to different objects
很多指向不同对象的指针
and so if you put a couple entries into
因此，如果您将几个条目
a hash set it takes 152 bytes to
散列集需要152个字节
represent a hash set with two entries so
代表具有两个条目的哈希集，因此
the new set implementation is much more
新设置的实现要多得多
compact so if you have a new immutable
紧凑，所以如果您有一个新的不变性
set with two entries it only takes 20
设置两个条目只需要20
bytes instead of 152 bytes so once again
字节而不是152个字节，所以再次
I will have to skip beyond this there
我将不得不跳过这里
couple a couple things the design
情侣设计
rationale here I'll post these slides on
基本原理，我将这些幻灯片发布到
on the web so that you can see them and
在网络上，以便您可以看到它们，
I'll also be available for for questions
我也可以提问
afterwards but I'll just move directly
之后，但我将直接移动
on to my summary here so the collections
在这里查看我的摘要，以便收集
framework is 19 years old and it's it's
框架已有19年的历史了
old but we're still working on it
旧的，但我们仍在努力
there are lots of new enhancements in
有很多新的增强功能
Java 8 we saw all those new default
Java 8我们看到了所有这些新的默认值
method
方法
that add new functionality to all the
为所有
existing collections and then in Java
现有集合，然后用Java
nine we have our collections convenience
九，我们的收藏方便
factories that provide new compact
提供新契约的工厂
immutable collections and they're much
不变的收藏，它们很多
much more convenient to write and I
写起来更方便，我
encourage you to go to the JDK 9
鼓励您使用JDK 9
download page and download JDK 9 it
下载页面并下载JDK 9 it
should be in any recent build and
应该在任何最近的版本中
encourage you to try them out so thank
鼓励您尝试一下，谢谢
you I'm sorry I don't think I have time
你对不起，我认为我没有时间
for questions but I'll be available
提出问题，但我可以联系
afterwards for a conversation thank you
之后进行对话谢谢
[Music]
[音乐]